The short strangle is similar
to the short straddle,
though the strikes of
the options defer.
This is also a trade
that benefits from decay
and decreased volatility
regardless of direction.
Because the strike
prices involved are
further apart than
a short straddle,
there is a lower risk
that this trade will
cause the investor
to face a loss.
The lower associated risk
means that the investor
receives a lower premium at
the outset for making the trade.
As were the short straddle,
profits is kept to
the initial premium while loss
is potentially unlimited.
The short strangle makes
maximum profits between
the two strike prices and
has two break even points.
To the downside the trade
makes money if the
stock stays above
the lower strike
price of the port
minus the sum of the
two premiums paid.
To the upside, the trade
makes money if the stock
stays below the upper
strike price for the coal,
plus the sum of the
two premiums paid.
Outside of these
break even points,
the trade has unlimited loss
potential in the event that
the share price continues
to increase or decrease,
though the downside potential
loss is limited by the fact
that the share price could only
fall to a minimum of zero.